

**UX Designer & Researcher** 

jamesdavidmoffet.com

in jamesdavidmoffet

## about

As a designer and researcher, I am obsessed with understanding the human interfaces by which technology delivers us into an alternative future. Yet, I have learned to temper this obsession, harnessing critical theory and a range of user-centered research and organizational engineering techniques to help me find room to redirect established practices by applying user-centered and systems-level thinking to the awesome challenge of improving people's experiences.

# education

2016 - 2018

## Harvard University Graduate School of Design

Master's degree, Design Technology Studies

# SKIIS

Design Research
UI/UX Design
Data Science
Software Engineering
Hardware Engineering
Public Speaking
Project Management
Product Design

# work experience

### OutVote.io

2017 - 2018 Cambridge, MA, USA Director of User Experience
 In 2017, Outvote acquired my civtech
 startup COMM!T, growing to a team of
 five. I direct an agile team of designers,
 coders and researchers to ensure that
 our product that meets the needs of our
 10 enterprise clients and 1000 users.

#### Independent Consulting

2016-2018 Cambridge, MA, USA

## - UXD/UXR Consultant

Collaborated with GoINVO on the MA SNAP web application redesign.
Consulted for City of Boston on FOIA process redesign. Designed open source citizen analytics apps for Cambridge.

## MIT Community Innovators Lab

2016 - 2017 Cambridge, MA, USA

### - Research Manager

Led a team of 12 researchers, designers and devs conducting field/remote user research on 1,200 grassroots organizing groups. Designed, built and deployed a collaborative mapping tool to help orgs discover each other and connect.

#### **Fulbright Fellow**

2015 - 2016 Budapest, HU

### - Lecturer and Researcher

Lectured on design at CEU and piloted OpenLab public design workshops, mentoring UXR, interface design and service prototyping for public projects.

#### **SEIU**

2009 - 2014 Portland, OR, USA

## Senior UX and Product Manager

Built a user-centered design and engineering team from the ground up, replacing 20-plus-yr-old software products handling all billing and member data. Increased net revenue by 10%, while reducing billing errors by 90%.